working with agents and LLMs introduces some new dimensions on security
that wouldn't normally think about.
text becomes something that can be vulnerable,
can have some executable intent,
A couple years ago, you would never worry about the security of a markdown document
the combination of some access to privileged information
or some private data, some exposure to some untrusted content,
maybe from the outside world and the ability to communicate externally.
And most agents, by default are going to have all of these three things.
And that is of where you're one prompt injection away from let's say bad time.
Yeah. Yeah.
The AI Native Dev is a podcast for developers and engineering
leads at the cutting edge of AI and agentic coding.
Join your hosts, Guy Podjarny and me, Simon Maple.
Every week as we chat with the most exciting voices in
AI and tackle the biggest questions facing developers today.
This is the AI Native Dev.
Back in November, we hosted
the first ever in-person AI Native Dev Con in New York.
This June 1st and second, we're bringing it to London.
It's two days built for AI Native developers and engineering teams, one day
full of hands on workshops and one day full of practical talks on
agent skills, context engineering, agent orchestration and enablement platforms
and how teams are actually shipping AI in production.
Join us at the Brewery in London near the Barbican for all of that,
plus networking parties, giveaways and a room full of people.
Building the future of AI native development.
You can also join us from anywhere in the world via the live stream.
As you're listening to this podcast.
You get 30% off your ticket with Code Pod 30.
Just head to AI native Dev Königssee and we'll see you in London.
Hello and
welcome to another episode of the AI Native Dev.
And on today's show, we're going to be tackling the big questions of how
organizations should be thinking about security in a development today,
not just for the security issues that we already know about that software
development has taught us over the years, but thinking about
some of the new security risks that agentic development brings.
Today Joining me on today's show, we have Joe Holdcroft,
a member of technical staff and team lead at Tessl.
Welcome, Joe. Thanks for having me back. Oh, absolutely.
And it is having you back because you joined.
Gosh, probably a good six months.
Nine months ago, we did a
we did a session all about how we use different agent tools.
And we actually swapped applications and played with that.
It was it was good fun.
But Joe, of course you are a member of technical staff,
a team lead here at all previously worked at Snyk.
Tell us a little bit about that. True.
Yeah, I worked at Snyk for three years, sort of during that hypergrowth period.
Mostly supporting the open source product.
Awesome.
And in between those two, you also a fractional CTO
and did a number of different mentoring gigs.
Really interesting to hear your point of view
around security and development from all of those experiences.
And very recently you actually work directly on the Snyk
and Tessl integration, adding security advisories and reports
into the Tessl registry for skills and context.
So some super cool stuff there.
Yeah, it's fun to get to work with some some old friends.
So why don't we jump in
and talk about how the attack surface has changed
and what we need to be concerned with from an agentic development point of view?
For sure.
I mean, lots to talk about here, but I think one of the best articulations
I've heard of this is in Simon Willison's Lethal Trifecta, where he talks
about the combination of three characteristics that all agents
pretty much have, which is some access to privileged information
or some private data, some exposure to some untrusted content,
maybe from the outside world and the ability to communicate externally.
And most agents, by default are going to have all of these three things.
And that is like a dangerous situation.
So you think about a coding agent that you're working with on your machine,
in a repository that has access to the code
and secrets that you have on your machine, which is your private data.
They're pulling in dependencies, documentation issues, search results
from the outside world. That's your untrusted content.
And they can run shell commands and hit HTTP endpoints and CLI commands.
And that's your communicating with the outside world.
And really those combination of three things is sort of
where you're one prompt injection away from let's say bad time.
Yeah. Yeah.
And it's interesting actually until you said prompt injection
there, a lot of those things are fairly consistent with, you know,
some of the issues we have now with the exception that,
you know, you have an agent doing it this time around.
So perhaps when we think about, you know,
what's what we need to, to, to do to make sure
we have solid code quality, solid, you know,
vulnerability management, those types of things.
You know, what is it?
We need to do to our existing processes to, to, to cater for these types of issues.
And there's a bunch of things you need to do.
But I think maybe the first thing to consider
is that a lot of the same considerations that you might have
for software that's written by humans is the same kind of thing
that you need to care about with agents.
I think of it's like a force multiplier, right?
It's all of the same hygiene that you'd be doing, making sure
you have your SCA scanning and your SaaS scanning
and your processes in the right place in terms of security.
All of that stuff becomes more important, not less important,
as agents are working on your code because, you know you can consider them
somebody that you might trust less than you otherwise would like.
For example, a, a contractor that you might get in
someone who's going to be writing a lot of code for you.
They'll kind of do whatever they're told.
Maybe they have a certain amount of access
to your internal systems, but there's not a huge amount of oversight
in kind of think of your agents in that way.
there are a few ways in which working with agents and LLMs introduces
some new kind of dimensions on security that we don't wouldn't
normally think about.
The most interesting one, I think, is text becomes
something that can be vulnerable, can have some executable intent, right?
A couple years ago, you would never worry
about the security of a markdown document anywhere in your organization.
And today that's actually very important.
markdown file that you're giving to an agent
could encode, you know, some vulnerability
to instruct the agent to go and do something malicious or just unsafe.
And that's just completely novel situation.
Yeah.
And it's interesting that a lot of the time
we we find ourselves, we get caught, catch ourselves talking about how agents
add security issues into into the space, but how reliable are agents
not just finding issues, but even, you know, being able
to start coding in a reliable way.
We've heard of things like mythos coming out.
Can we rely upon and do you rely upon agents to identify issues
and help you guide you into making sure you develop more securely?
I think you can for sure.
I mean, agents are always kind of backwards looking,
so there's like a little bit of a lag before things are going to catch up
with new types of attack vectors and new vulnerabilities.
But absolutely.
I mean, and I think
it's kind of the only effective defense that we have against the kind of
that you can introduce into text documents and markdown files
these days is to have another LLM judge that content and see
if it kind of seems risky, because static analysis is not going to cut it here.
There's many ways you can phrase something to kind of
not even trick an agent, but encourage an agent to do something that maybe
isn't what you're what the consumer is intending.
So so I guess the classic question is, do AI coding tools
make developers more or less likely to ship vulnerabilities these days?
Yeah, I think it really depends.
So of course, you know, agents are allowing you to be
a lot more productive and ship a lot more features and a lot more code
and more Kodi.
Right.
The more chances you have of introducing vulnerabilities.
But also they're pretty good at like following patterns as well.
So, you know, if you have good, well-established patterns in your code
base, it make it quite difficult for you
to be vulnerable to things like SCL injection, for example.
Then they're going to tend to follow those patterns.
But then on the other hand, if you haven't got well-established patterns
or you're you're not managing the context with your agent.
Well, to sort of encourage them to do things
in the way that you need them to be done, then they're going to fall back
on training data.
And the training data obviously, is like a wealth of insecure
open source software that is out there in the world today.
Yeah.
And you get
going back to what you mentioned previously about text being vulnerable.
That's really interesting because there are very few patterns.
It kind of reminds me a little bit like what security.
Like when you think about something that whereby the input can change
very, very slightly and go round a rule that is a preexisting rule.
Essentially, you know, what happens when text can become a vulnerability.
Things can be phrased in a slightly different way,
or things can be approached from a different angle,
and you can't have static tests for every single thing.
So you very often do rely on a kind of LLM as a judge,
assessing whether certain text is potentially dangerous or not.
So when you think about skills, a skills MD is essentially a bunch of text.
And that text describes and guides an agent into doing something
a particular way in order to be able to identify whether that's malicious or not.
One of the things that was added
to the Tessl registry recently by yourself and the team is that ability to
to scan the skills with Snyk and get those results via Tessl.
Tell us a little bit about that.
Yeah.
So we've introduced Snyks agents scan tooling into into the product.
So everything that's published
to the registry now goes goes through this skill scan.
And also we're indexing a bunch of skills sort of out there
on GitHub and running security scans for those as well.
So if you're trying to install these things with Tessl, then
we're going to warn you if something is like has something that we think
might be malicious or maybe, you know, mal intent.
The other interesting angle on this is a lot of the potential security
risk are kind of contextual.
So, you know, a skill contacting the outside world
or using some API may not necessarily be a bad thing.
You know, Tessl has a skill that is using the Tessl API.
That seems fair enough.
It's important that the scanner has that kind of context, but a lot of the time,
really what you need to do is surface that to to the consumer, to the user.
Right.
Like of course, many of the skills
I'm going to be using are contacting the outside world in some way.
But am I okay with this skill using this particular
API or this particular CLI command?
And is that appropriate with what the skill is trying to do?
So we're sort of working on evolving the user experience a little more to
not just flag up things that are like obviously malicious
packages, because a lot of the cases, it's a little more subtle than that, that
perhaps this skill is doing a little bit more than you might be comfortable with.
If you just skimmed the skill MD, you might not realize that it's also going
in hitting GitHub and posting some of your personal information there, for example.
a lot of the issues that we've talked about already
are some of which people will be very familiar with, others
are completely new, and it's just a growth in the attack
vector that we have as attack surface rather.
One of the styles is
something like a supply chain, dependency risk.
Sometimes it can be
you can look at that from the libraries that we actually import.
Other times it's supply chain through the context.
Let's talk about what's already existing.
Let's talk about libraries first and then we'll jump onto the other.
So when we think about libraries and AI agents using libraries to
to assist with, with its abstraction you know, what should we be worried about
when an AI is trying to or rather, an agent
is trying to choose a library when it wants to to perform
a certain task?
There's a number of things to think about here.
And the first one, as with many of these things, is just like velocity.
More code means more packages are getting added, which is harder to review.
And maybe you're going to be less detailed with a review that you're doing.
One of the other things to keep in mind is that, you know, a lot of the time,
a agent is just going to hallucinate a package name.
It's just going to guess at something and see if it's there and install it.
And there's a a beautiful new phrase that's popped up called slop squatting
to sort of describe this, this attack vector
where people can upload malicious packages on package names
that they think in them is likely to pick for some kind of scenario, to then
get that into your into your supply chain, which is an interesting one.
And the other thing to keep in mind is that agents these days at least,
are not really looking at packages in the same way that a human might.
I think like if I'm choosing an open source package, I'm not just looking
for the first search result that matches the kind of task that I'm trying to do.
I'm also looking at them for some social proof,
you know, how many stars do they have? Are they?
Well established that they've been around a long time.
They sponsored by a company or an individual,
all of these kind of things that an agent typically isn't looking at.
It will, you know,
maybe pick something that's well represented in the training data
or just something that kind of matches its its search of what it's trying to do.
Well.
So there are a few new things to consider here.
There will be a phrase that we use in today's podcast,
which is going to sound rude, but weirdly slop squatting, is not it?
Well. Not. The worst. Move on to that.
We'll move on to that.
Let's go on to thinking about the supply chain of context now.
And this is interesting
because, you know, essentially when we look at the supply chain
of dependencies, it's about us being comfortable trusting
the third party libraries content code that we're pulling into our organization,
to our application, our project, and we think about the same thing.
But for context.
This is more of a development time thought process
of we're not shipping this necessarily, but we're using this context
to guide our agent to write appropriate code.
First of all, how important is it that we know who these people are,
how many skills we're using in our organization?
How important is that given it's a development of thing?
I think it's hugely important, and it's an interesting topic for me
because I think it's almost like we've got so excited with the capabilities
that we have now with agents and skills that we've kind of forgotten about,
you know, ten, 20 years of of software engineering
and what we've learned about software supply chain and open source.
And, you know, people are freely pulling in skills
from random GitHub repo, pulling in main,
updating that, you know, frequently without really having any oversight.
This is not typically how we deal with third party open source software anymore.
You know, we're using properly version software.
You know,
a lot of the time you're looking at only pulling in things of a certain age
because, you know,
you want to protect against these kind of supply chain attacks
that we're seeing more and more of these days.
You're
interested in some kind of like provenance where this is actually coming from.
A lot of that has kind of gone out of the window.
And this is really something that we care a lot about, a lot
at Tessl, and that we're investing a lot of energy into building,
you know, a package, a registry for package context in the same way
that you have many registries
for open source software that kind of just bring a lot of these same things.
You know, it's not like hugely novel,
you know, new approaches.
It's the same kind of approach to the, the new,
the new kind of context, the new material, I suppose.
So it's time to drop the C bomb.
First time on the podcast.
We've heard about the S bomb, the software bill of materials.
Do we need a C bomb, a context bill of materials so that we can identify
for this project, for this development scope, we know what context
we are using, where we're pulling it in from, versioned, etc., etc..
Is that something you feel your teams could, you know, provide value from?
Absolutely. Yeah.
And another thing we're looking at Tessl and I think, it's
it's it's an important aspect that's missing at the moment.
And again,
potentially more complicated than it is with things like s bombs, for example.
You may also need to cover context that is just running on a developers
machine globally.
There's sort of different different scopes, right,
that you can kind of install and get something into an agent's context.
So okay, I haven't got anything that looks scary in my projects.
Maybe I'm even checking that in a CI action using Tessl's Tessl CLI.
But what about what developers installing on their machines
and how can I restrict that is, you know, another layer of complexity
here that I think we haven't even started to touch the slides on.
Yeah, I guess the auditing or the gating of, context
in a similar way that we would think about dependencies and, and almost
it starts to raise the questions of, okay, at what stage do we do that in terms of
do you want developers to want to be creative,
want to build fast and have a gating station a little bit later?
There's a whole bunch of interesting things that could be happening.
Do you have opinions on that now, or is this something that you feel
we as an organization are evolving through?
I think it depends on your use case and, and sort of
how restrictive or kind of liberal you want to be.
But again, a lot of the, the, the fundamental
tools are missing right now.
So maybe talk a bit a little bit about Tessl CLI
which is going to put a manifest in your project.
So this is something that you can
you can go and do some checks in your CI if you want.
What are the different pieces of context that we have installed.
How what's their security rating.
You know, do we trust them.
Are they in some allow lists that I might have without the manifest?
You can't do any of those things.
You can't even really have the opinion about how much you want to secure
your projects.
Yeah, yeah.
Actually built a little tool that I showed at demo time
a while back that looks at your Tessl.
JSON looks at all of the all of the pieces
of context that the skills that you're using.
And based on the results from Snyk via the Tessl API,
kind of like pull together this. Nice.
Almost like a security report, a posture security posture
style report or, you know, for your application, for your project.
This is what this is what, you know, this this is where the issues exist.
And I think people are going to be asked for that more and more in terms of,
you know, don't just freely pick whatever you want.
Let's actually have a look at what we're using now.
Yeah.
What about other things like, you know, whether it's secrets and credentials,
for example, some more core
security style concerns,
is this also an issue for agentic development?
Are there new things that we should be wary of when when
thinking about how to hide those credentials?
Yeah, absolutely.
I think this is, part of the more a more fiddly part of the equation here.
You know,
the the agent has amazing access to privileged information on your machine.
So even if you think about
your environment variable file for a very common way to be working,
can you and do
you and how do you prevent the agent from reading that file?
And because if it can read that file, you can assume that that is going
to end up somewhere that you don't want, right?
Like it also has the ability to post information out on the internet,
and even just the fact that that might be read in means
that it's it's in logs at various places of, you know, your stack
and probably with the model providers as well.
And if it can read files, why couldn't it read that file?
So, you know, maybe you want to start looking at different mechanisms
where you have, you know, like a secret broker
and your issuing more like just in time credentials with like short, short lived
TLS so that, you know, some code does get out there.
You don't need to worry about it because it's only valid for 15 minutes.
So much. But this is.
Yeah. Again, it's kind of,
typical security hygiene, but
it's a at a new level of abstraction
that is much trickier to deal with because it's running on your machine
as if it's a developer that you would trust.
Yeah, yeah.
And I think that's that's a key phrase there.
It's running a machine like a developer.
And I think there was
I was reading a Reddit
thread the other day where there were people who were using an agent
and they'd essentially said, I think it was called code.
And they said, look, you can't through the settings, you can't
you don't have access to the end file, as a, as a file read.
And what Claude Code did was it wrote
a bash script that essentially read from the file.
And it's not it's not trying to circumvent security per se.
It's got a problem that it's trying to solve, and it's trying to work out
how, given the tools it has, it can it can perform that.
And a lot of people are replying saying, look,
what you essentially want to do is run it as a particular user that doesn't have
an doesn't have actual access to this file through the operating system.
And it's it's really about trying to find that mechanism, a good mechanism where,
it can't gain access to that.
And So it's kind of like, leans into the a principle of least privilege,
which, you know,
everyone's all familiar with
from a normal coding point of view from an agent coding point of view.
What are the types of guardrails or controls we need to put in place to
achieve that in a
software development environment?
Yeah, I mean, there's some good hygiene things worth looking at.
You know, sandboxing your agent locally is going to reduce
kind of blast radius of some things that can go on on your machine.
And then really, you know, you're not going to get a lot of success
telling the agent not to do certain things because you know, it will find a way
around, as you had your example a minute ago, which is a great example.
So really you need to look at like, how can you sort of strangle access
at the right level.
So maybe that's some sort of network egress controls, you know,
which domains can you be talking to.
Capability based permissions.
So you know which repos can you work with.
What how are you setting up your your git remotes.
What kind of pushing can you do.
What actions do you have running on branches where agents can push to
and then thinking about things that are dangerous and
and putting in approval gates that are not just like,
you know, please stop and ask the human.
It's like it's physically impossible to do that without some kind of approval
that then generates a hash. Then you can kind of push it through.
But really, it's an
interesting it's an interesting situation
because there isn't really like an escalation of privilege here,
you know, like you're running an agent on developers machine.
Typically, that agent has the same kinds of permissions that the developer does,
and typically you're not going to be able to tell the difference
between the developer or the developer, plus the agent
hitting the various different services that they might be using.
Because essentially it's performing actions on your behalf
with your credentials. Yeah. 100%.
How do we avoid because like, you know, we we can always add
more and more security controls in security guardrails.
How do we avoid securing ourselves into bankruptcy where the cost of over
securing or securing ourselves actually starts
having an impact on our companies?
You know, time pressures of hitting that deadline, speed of delivery,
those types of things.
Yeah, it's an uncomfortable conversation
because I think the first thing to accept is that this is a nascent field.
We're, you know, we're still figuring things out.
And if you're going to be using agents, you kind of need to accept that
there's going to be perhaps some breach at some point.
So really, maybe what you need to do is be prepared and figure out
what your risk tolerance is and where your risk tolerance is.
So, I sometimes like to think about this, about how reversible something is.
So if something is kind of like low risk and reversible,
those are the kind of tasks
that you might want to be giving to an agent autonomously working in a branch,
you know, not a huge deal and pushing something up to the git remote.
Probably not a huge deal.
Do you want to give the agent control to, like, push directly to production?
I probably wouldn't, you know, that's that's
that's a lot less reversible than working within a feature branch, for example.
Yeah, yeah.
And offline, we were talking a little bit about how you kind of consider
an agent's to effectively be similar to an employee,
where you almost, you know, you trust them as much as you do.
Maybe it's more of a junior employee, maybe it's more of a, you know,
someone who's a contractor or something like that, thinking about
where you draw the line on how much autonomy an agent has,
is it similar to the kind of thought processes you go through?
If someone's just joining the team and you want to you want them to be,
you know, autonomous enough but equally validating what they're doing.
Yeah.
Again, I think about it as like a sliding scale with the with the risks. So,
I can maybe talk about an example that I have where,
you know, mostly my agent is working directly on code
and sort of pushing things from my machine autonomously.
But even when it comes to, say, PR reviews, if I'm getting some feedback
on a PR, either from a colleague or from, you know, one of the
AI PR review systems that we use.
I want to be in the loop there, but it's also like kind of low risk.
Like if the agent posts a comment that makes me look silly.
That's not ideal at work, but I'm not like breaking production.
So there.
I've used a skill where I've kind of asked the agent to analyze
the comments and come up with a plan and talk to me and wait for my approval
a couple times, kind of before pushing something through.
Whereas again, I can only use like the pushing to production,
it just doesn't have that ability. So, you know,
I'm not using I'm not relying on a skill to stop it from doing that.
But presumably it can get so far before there needs to be some human intervention
to check or to have some ability to say, yeah, I agree with what you've done.
I can now push to production
or I will allow you to push the production or something like that, I guess.
What do those checkpoints look like for irreversible actions?
Yeah, I mean, personally, I just haven't implemented those kinds of checkbooks,
those kinds of checkpoints for high danger, irreversible actions because,
how do you trust that the
agent is going to follow that instruction if if the checkpoint is, so.
The checkpoints are autonomous.
The chuck points are part of the autonomous system.
Yeah.
So like in my PR review example, it's like part of the skill.
So I'll invoke the skill when I want to do a PR review.
And in the skill I say,
you know, make sure you check with me and blah blah blah blah blah.
But that's kind of fairly low risk.
If you wanted to have a checkpoint for something like push to production,
actually systematically making it so the agent can't push the production
until there's human confirmation, like, how do you build that system?
Yeah. Yeah.
Like, with without just saying, please ask for permission
before running this scary command that actually you can always run.
You know, it's kind of about trust.
Like, how much do you trust the agent?
And you probably shouldn't with those kind of things. Yeah.
And and when we do think about that human oversight,
how good are we as humans are?
I guess, you know, we know.
We know we've always been pretty bad at reading other people's code.
Naturally.
Anyway, as the amount increases,
how good are we going to be as humans to actually monitor
what agents are doing and actually say, yes, yes, yes, this is fine.
This is fine versus actually making sure we do go into depth with the with
almost like the stringent methodologies of code reviews and things like that.
Do we do we actually need to lean more onto,
you know, testing and deterministic code reviews as well as AI code
reviews to essentially manage and maintain that, yes,
this code is correct because I can see all this has been tested and passed.
Or is there a lot more manual intervention that humans need to make?
Yeah, I mean, this is the other big thing that changes not just in security,
but like in general, software engineering is the
this sort of asymmetric velocity agents can do like a ton of things.
You can invoke a bunch of them to do a lot,
and we can't sort of clone ourselves in the same way.
Yeah, yeah.
So how do you avoid kind of becoming the bottleneck?
And I think same principles kind of apply at every point, you know,
what do you care about?
Maybe, you know, a certain point, you really care that, like, the code style
guide is being followed and PR reviews might be more focused around that?
I don't think anybody's particularly interested so much in that anymore.
The parts that you are interested, you're going to make sure
that's like automated and linting and really like
if you if you have limited attention, where are you going to focus it now?
So, a selecting the PR that you're going to have more oversight over than others,
you know, something's touching the auth service probably needs some human eyes.
Some details humanize,
you know,
if something
kind of seems like it's dealing with some new customer data or something,
you might want to be paying more attention there.
Where can and then when you're actually doing the review,
what kind of things can you lean on to help you?
Like, can you use another LLM as a judge on this
to kind of give you a bit of a report that you can then look at,
rather than having to crawl through all the code from scratch?
And yeah, which things can you kind of automate a way
so that you can spend more time focusing on the higher risk areas, like
where can you leverage your time really, I think is the thing to be thinking about
all kind of points of the stack there, because we will always be the bottleneck.
We're kind of just moving where in the development process that bottleneck is.
And if something bad did go through into production, how does the,
the auditability and the logging, how is that affected by agentic method?
Because as you kind of mentioned, you know, there could be multiple actors
here, like could be the individual me or you
that's working with a group of agents.
There could be a number of different models,
a number of different agents that we're working with.
How do we actually identify where these types of issues come through
when when there's so much behind potentially a single user commit.
Yeah. It's an interesting one.
I think, you know, all of what we've done in the past still counts.
You know the traceability of like a commit through CD
into production and then your telemetry on top of that.
But there's kind of a new dimension that also becomes important now,
which is like what actually happened on the developers machine.
And you know, how did you arrive at the the code that got committed?
Because that's going to help you understand
how how can you avoid this kind of thing from happening again.
So being able to cross-reference, not only the commit to the issue,
but the commit to the session that was had with the agent
and maybe what skills were invoked
and what context was in the context window is going to help you understand.
Yeah. How do we actually get to this point?
And then also, you know,
looking at things that we already have like the PR reviews and like how did
how did this not get caught by your, say a PR review system?
So all of the same things that we had before are important.
And again, just to go back to the supply chain thing, understand it,
like having some kind of manifest and some kind of versioning on
those skills is helpful here as well, because, okay, you had the developers
machine had this particular skill and oh, I wonder why it didn't work.
What version was it at?
Where was it installed?
And I think at the minute we're not very well equipped to answer these questions.
Yeah, it'll be interesting when we when we can and we can determine
if it came from this place or that place when we think about accountability
and who's accountable for for the software if it's got a bug in it.
There's this wonderful episode of The Office, the UK office
where Gareth, he's he's on the phone to a calculator company,
and he said, I built this quote out for a for one of our clients
and, well, I've eliminated all other aspects.
I believe it's down to the calculator.
And so, you know, when something does go wrong, you know,
what do we need to look at?
Is it the individual who is running the agent?
Is it the team that together are allowing code to go into production?
Is it the agent itself?
What typically is the accountable piece that we need to
that we need to work through?
I mean, I don't know how far blaming the agent gets. You.
Might make you feel a bit better.
You're absolutely right.
So yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
You know, I it's a tool, right?
So and the it's there to sort of serve us.
So I think, you know, really it's the team
are accountable and like the processes that got you there.
I'm sure there's no like mal intent normally with these kind of things.
But how did this kind of thing happen.
How did we allow it to happen.
The interesting questions there I think.
But yeah, I don't think you'll get very far with blaming an agent or even,
you know, the frontier model companies in this kind of thing.
Hey everyone!
Hope you're enjoying the episode so far.
Our team is working really hard behind the scenes to bring you the best guests,
so we can have the most informative conversations about agentic development,
whether that's talking about the latest
tools, the most efficient workflows, or defining best practices.
But for whatever reason, many of you have yet to subscribe to the channel.
If you're enjoying the podcast and want us to continue to bring you
the very best content.
Please do us a favor and hit that subscribe button.
It really does make a difference and lets us continue to improve
the quality of our guests and build an even better product for you.
All right, back to the episode.
When we think about humans and the cultural changes that we need to
to make, obviously at Tessl here, we're hyper into AI
and we're very AI first with the native, the way we are building software.
But is it healthy still to have a level of skepticism, a healthy skepticism
when using agents to, to, to build
code versus being having an over agency
to, to to models and agents and almost having too much trust.
Where's the right balance there where we're not all in on AI?
Yeah. I mean it's it's so subjective isn't it?
I think it really depends on your use case and your risk tolerance.
You know, a big investment bank is probably going to be quite different
to a seed stage startup in kind of the things
that they're optimizing for and also their risk tolerance.
I think some of the things that would apply
well to everybody is like thinking about what is our
AI governance strategy and who owns it,
maybe whatever size, even if it's we don't really have one
and it's the CEO owns it, you know, putting a little bit of thought into that.
But larger organizations that we're talking to are,
you know, interested in all kinds of like governance tooling here.
You know, a lot of the same, hygiene things that you would normally have, you
know, your branch protection, your SaaS, your SCA, thinking about your logging
and your retention of those logs
and maybe rethinking how you do secrets.
I think this one thing that agents do change is your approach to secrets is
may may have served you well for humans, and that might start to fall apart
a little with agents.
And but then in terms of the actual agency you're using,
which agents are okay to use, and then it's
and then it's really the context piece, which is again
what we're focusing on at Tessl, like what context is allowed to be pulled in
which things are pushed to developers so they can't forget about
or they can't be missing.
So we.
Just say it's almost like skepticism through, you know, having real visibility
and transparency to the issues that that each of these things occur.
So like when you say, you know, what the models do have, don't have access to,
it's about seeing how they trip over, seeing how
they fall over, and recognizing, this agent is not great at this.
And understanding that kind of like skepticism through transparency.
Yeah, I suppose that but again, you know, depending on your
on your wrist tolerance, you might,
you might want to start with a much more sort of lockdown
environment and see how things work and sort of slowly add abilities.
But,
you know, I think
you're going to get the fastest results by moving fast and breaking things.
It's just maybe thinking about what things you're breaking up front,
you know, if you're moving fast
and breaking production, that might not be so good.
If you're moving fast and, you know, breaking your development process,
that's probably interesting if you're trying to move quickly.
So let's let's roll up.
Let's wrap up with two more questions.
First of all, what would you say is the most underrated security risk
that you see organizations take adopting agentic development tools.
Yeah.
Again, I probably sound like a broken record at this point,
but I do think it's this the context supply chain piece.
I think it's really interesting how, you know, we're just installing context
into our agents
in the same way that you might just pull something in from a repo pre
npm or various package manager days.
Folks are finding all kinds of skills
on developer machines and in their repos that have come from all over the place.
Maybe they don't even necessarily know where they've come from
or who's authored them.
They haven't gone through any kind of scanning.
There's no companies that have their factory set up,
but you can still just pull in any skill into any repo or into your machine.
So I really think it's this whole, the whole supply chain of context.
How do you get that into your projects?
How do you get that into your machines?
And how can an organization have more oversight and more control over that,
and how you can have more trust in those pieces?
I think it's a governance issue that people are calling out for.
Here is one of the reasons why Tessl are really are really doubling down on that.
And a wrap up question, then,
if you could give one piece of security advice to a CTO who's
the company have just decided to go all in on development, what would that be?
Yeah, I mean, so many detailed things, but I guess
just at a high level to think of the agent as like a very competent, fluent,
but somewhat inexperienced contractor, or like inexperienced
in your context, how would you work with those kind of folks?
You know, you'd probably bring them in.
You'd give them a bunch of code to write.
You give them a bunch of projects to work on.
You'd probably be thoughtful
about which production systems you give them access to.
Like, you can work in dev, but you know,
we're not going to let you push your access fraud directly.
You probably would make sure at least their first couple
PR are getting some proper good human review.
You check their references, check their work a little bit.
So I think I find that framing kind of helpful to think
to think about things in a way where,
you know, you're not doubling down so hard that you're tying shoelaces together.
But, you know, you're also being thoughtful about, you know,
there is some risk here.
So perhaps so perhaps dress up
a mannequin in the office, call them Claud, and and, you know,
pretend that they're quite a junior less experience, maybe a contractor.
And then every time you think about giving an agent something, you know,
that's, you know, potentially damaging, potentially irreversible,
would you give it to that, that,
that mannequin that, that more inexperienced dev in the room?
Probably not.
Think about that twice when giving to an agent. Yeah for sure.
Yeah. Amazing.
Joe, it's been a pleasure again.
And thank you very much for all the time today. It's been great.
Thanks for having me. Awesome.
Thanks very much for joining us on today's episode.
I really hope you enjoyed it and tune in to the next one.
Bye for now.
The AI Native Dev is brought to you by the package manager for skills and context.
Your hosts are Guy Podjarny and me, Simon Maple.
Our producer is Tom Dowler.
The AI Native Dev is not just a podcast, it's a community.
And we host monthly meetups at the Tessl offices in central London.
Visit Tessl IO forward slash community to learn more and I hope to see you there.